<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Diana Cai</title>
    <link>https://dicai.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Diana Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dicai.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tips for New PhD Students in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://dicai.github.io/post/tips-new-phd-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dicai.github.io/post/tips-new-phd-students/</guid>
      <description>Starting a PhD in itself is full of many challenges, but students starting this fall will have to navigate the extra hurdle of a virtual environment. Here I’m attempting to write down what I’d tell my junior colleagues starting a PhD in the US &amp;ndash; geared toward students in Computer Science, and especially Machine Learning &amp;ndash; including some Princeton-specific thoughts.
Navigating the academic landscape In graduate school, you get an immense amount of freedom to choose how to spend your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding Resources for Junior Women in Machine Learning and Statistics</title>
      <link>https://dicai.github.io/post/funding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dicai.github.io/post/funding/</guid>
      <description>Fellowships, Scholarships, and Grants Below is a list of fellowships, scholarships, and grants for graduate students, typically geared toward women or underrepesented groups in computing:
Microsoft Ada Lovelace PhD Fellowship: 2nd year PhD students at time of application Microsoft Dissertation Grant: 4th year PhD or above at time of application Women Techmakers Scholarship: undergraduate, masters, and PhD students Gertrude M. Cox Scholarship: MS or PhD students Adobe Research Women-in-Technology Scholarship: undergraduates and masters students Loreal USA for Women in Science: postdoctoral fellowship Conference support Many organizations offer travel awards for graduate students and postdocs to attend conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
